Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
Episode 94
Allah!
Allah! Allah! Allah! Allah!
Inegöl will be your grave, Osman Bey!
Your grave!
Soldiers! Defend the castle!
With your lives!
Allah is one! Allah is one! Allah is one!
For Rome!
Today is the day for matyrdom!
Allah is one! Allah is one! Allah is one!
Show mercy to those who seek!
Draw your swords to those who seek wrath!
Come on, alps!
Allah is one! Allah is one! Allah is one!
Come on, lions!
Come on!
Allah is one!
Gündüz Bey!
Today is the day.
Allah is one!
Gündüz Bey!
My Bey!
Are you all right, my Bey?
We will take...
...the castle! I won't leave you!
Cerkutay is here!
You are fine, my Bey!
You are fine.
Gündüz Bey!
Gündüz Bey! Gündüz Bey!
Alps!
Fight until there is no infidel left!
Burn the walls, destroy them! Attack!
My Bey!
You are fine!
You are fine, my Bey!
Don't die, please!
Nikola!
Soldier!
Retreat!
My Bey!
I know a way to enter from the back!
Come on, then!
Holy Jesus, you made a sacrifice for us.
You paid for the sin of the first man by
crucifixion.
Now, this city is paying the price
because of Nikola.
Father, Son and Holy Spirit.
Protect my people.
Don't make the innocents pay for Lord
Nikola's idiocy.
Amen.
Save yourselves! The Turks are in
Inegöl!
They are everywhere!
Run! Run!
God, remind the Turks of their mercy.
My Bey...
...Nikola filled the door with soldiers.
Nikola's moves are now redundant.
He can't do anything.
We've done a lot of impossible things.
Come on, valiants. Come on!
Noone will pass this door!
No one!
Brother, it was our destiny to fight back
to back and...
...be a martyr.
Thankfully, we die for the conquest,
for Allah.
Sisters! Shoot!
Allah is one!
Attack!
Come on!
Help me!
Let's open this.
He ran away.
Is there a passage here?
Where can he go in his own castle, Turgut
Bey?
That dog must have thought of something.
Nikola.
You can't go anywhere.
Anywhere.
Nephew.
You've been with them for a long time.
You know all about them.
But there is something you don't.
And they hide it very well.
You were like their soldier.
They seem quick.
They seem fearless.
But they are cowards.
And they hide it very well.
They have passages everywhere in case
something happens.
Let's find Nikola before he escapes.
Nikola.
They are such cowards that they even build
they passages...
...under where they sit.
My Bey!
Inegöl has fallen, my Bey.
Our soldiers are flowing through
the walls and gates!
Thanks to Allah!
Nikola's head is all that is left.
Don't worry.
We will take that too.
Turgut Bey.
You stay here and provide security.
Don't, Osman Bey.
Are you going after Nikola alone?
No.
The brave men who gave good news will
come after me.
Aktemur, meet Inegöl's people.
Tell them that...
...no innocent people will be harmed.
As you order, my Bey!
Come on, alps!
Osman Bey, the revenge of the innocent
people depend on you now.
Cut his breath so that they can find
peace.
Nikola has nowhere to run now.
This will be over today.
Thank you.
Come on! In the name of Allah!
Brothers.
The love of Jesus Christ is with us.
Don't worry.
Besides, you know that the Turks took
Bilecik.
But they did not harm any of our
coreligionists there.
The Turks were also friendly to the
Christians living with them in Söğüt.
As long as we don't draw a sword to them,
they will show us mercy.
Don't be afraid, pray.
Trust the Priest.
Don't fear.
Us, Turks, we never hurt the innocents.
On the contrary...
...we stand against those who try to
harm them.
You are the commander who saved me from
the torture in the dungeon.
So, you are a Turk.
I should've known this from your mercy.
Yes.
I'm not a Roman commander.
I am Turkish.
He is a Turk!
But don't worry.
As long as Osman Bey swings the flag of
Islam on these walls...
...you will neither starve nor be hurt.
You will live in good conditions.
Thank you!
Turks do not defeat their enemies with
their swords but with mercy.
Their mercy that is more cruel than their
sword.
Aktemur!
Gündüz Bey...
...is wounded.
Gündüz Bey is wounded, Ayşe Hatun.
Gündüz!
Drink this, Gündüz Bey.
Open your mouth.
You will recover, my Bey.
You will recover.
We have many infidels to attack like
wolves!
Gündüz!
Gündüz Bey!
Ayşe! Ayşe! Ayşe!
Gündüz!
Father!
Why didn't you take him to the healing
tent?
I am telling you, Cerkutay!
Why is he still here?
Kumral Abdal told us not to move those
who fall and inform me.
We called him, Ayşe Sister. He must be
on his way.
Fall? What fall?
He fell from the wall...
...while fighting.
Gündüz! Gündüz! I am here.
Gündüz, I am here.
Look, Aktemur is here too. Our son is
here.
Look.
Son.
Father.
I am here, father.
Son.
I couldn't protect Gündüz Bey.
Stupid Cerkutay! Stupid Cerkutay!
Stupid Cerkutay!
Don't, Cerkutay! Don't!
Gündüz.
I am here!
I am here, Gündüz Bey!
Hang on, Gündüz. We will take you home.
Take the wounded to the healing tent
first!
Even the enemies. They are still people.
Don't show us mercy!
Kill us!
You took our castle! You can kill us!
We do not persecute those who stand
bravely, even if the enemies.
We have come to hold the oppressors
to account.
And we will.
My Osman Bey will find that dog Nikola.
You are our prisoners now.
But know that as long as you are not
hostile to us...
...you will see nothing from us but mercy.
Take the prisoners.
Nikola must have set a trap.
-Be careful.
-As you order, my Bey!
Come on, my Orhan.
Come on, my Shahzada.
You must have left a trace behind you.
There is no trace of him. What do we do
now?
Don't worry. We surely will find
something.
Don't worry, sister.
We will save our Orhan.
I hope so, sister. I hope so.
Malhun Hatun! Bala Hatun!
They obviously stayed the night here.
The traces go this way.
Hatuns!
There is another trace.
They may have gone this way too.
Do you think they separated?
Or...
...do they want to deceive us?
Who are these people, Bala?
It is my mistake.
I gave Holofira to the soldiers just like
that.
How would you even know, sister?
We were deceived by their disguise.
We couldn't have known.
You never know what these dogs will do.
We musth search both ways.
Let's separate into two and search then.
You are right, Bala Hatun.
This is the best way.
Alps! Come with me.
Come on, sisters! This way!
It is hard to go on foot. We need horses.
Don't think about horses.
First, we have to find somewhere to hide
these kids.
Caves?
Osman knows the caves like the back of
his hand. No way.
Let's take a breath. Then we will go to
Master Arius' secret place.
Holofira...
...that necklace was very important to
you.
Why?
I wanted to leave it to you as a memory.
I know you will take good care of it
as well as I do.
Of course, I will. What is important to
you is important to me.
But I must give you something as well.
You can if we can survive this.
We will, I hope.
My mother and father won't leave us here.
Can you reach it?
The dagger. Can you take it?
Damn it! They are escaping!
Hang on.
Take this. Put this on your wound.
Wait here.
What will heal us is the death of Nikola,
my Bey.
We will take care of ourselves.
Thank you.
Stay here.
Hang on. Hang on, valiants!
There are traces here!
This charcoal trail.
Baysungur!
This is the second charcoal trail we see.
This may be from Orhan.
Right, Bala Hatun.
The traces increase as we go on.
These traces must be from my Shahzada.
My smart boy! He knows we will go after
him!
Come on!
We are on the right path, thankfully.
We will find our Shahzada, sister!
Only a little is left!
We will, sister. We will.
There is trace here too!
Hang on, son.
Your mother's going to save you.
Let's go! Get a move on!
Come, Osman Bey.
Come.
For God's sake, Osman Bey.
Do you think I'm the type of guy to...
...take some gold and flee his castle?
I'm not that guy.
I got two devotions:...
...one of them is Rome,...
...the other is the revenge
I'll get from you.
Revenge, huh?
Good.
I am right in front of you.
This is the time to get revenge.
I already lost my castle.
But you didn't win a whole lot either.
I took İnegöl.
So,...
...your life is next.
I took a lot from you as well, Osman Bey.
I took your loved ones away from you.
Do you remember your brother?
I gave you a promise when those two
senile old men were on the throne for...
...Sultanship and emperorship.
I said that I was going to
kill you with my bare hands.
I always keep my promises,...
...Osman Bey.
Come at me.
We're running towards
the way we came from.
I put tracks behind us...
...they'll find us eventually.
Let's go.
You're very smart, Orhan.
Come on, keep running.
My brother must have sent help.
Hide behind me.
I told you before not to
dare to escape again.
I'm not going to waste my
energy with you again.
Kill them.
We're here son!
I told you they were going to save us.
Damn it!
My brave son!
My beautiful girl.
Are you guys alright?
We knew you would come, mother.
Thank goodness, my son! Thank goodness!
Thank goodness!
You couldn't even take care
of a couple of kids, you fools!
That's why...
...you've got to be careful when
you choose the men beside you.
Kids getting shot is not good at all.
So, Barkın Bey...
...it fell to my lot once again.
My Orhan.
Thank goodness!
You weren't scrared much, right?
We were scared at first.
But then, we believed that you would come.
Orhan made me believe it.
Praise be, my valiant prince!
I knew you wouldn't let us down.
My smart boy.
Nikola.
Today, only my promise will be kept.
You,...
...you attacked my lineage.
You, you attacked my lineage.
Come here!
You attacked my religion.
Come!
You attacked my tribe.
You spilled the blood of my loved ones.
Come here!
You,...
...you...
...you can take nothing from me, Nikola.
I will get rid of you.
But, you won't get rid of me easily.
You won't get rid of me easily.
I took İnegöl from you.
İnegöl...
...İnegöl belongs to Turks, from now on.
And I planted the flag of Islam
in the middle of İnegöl.
Osman in the castle, and his hatuns
and children will die in the forest.
Listen to me...
...look at those dead soldiers
on the ground very carefully.
If any of you make one mistake...
...you will end up the same way as them.
My Orhan,...
...whose dogs are these?
Did they say anything?
No, Mother Bala.
But there was another guy leading them.
He fleed once you guys arrived.
You saved Kaya alps from getting poisoned.
Praise be, you brave kids!
That was Fira's talent, aunt Selvi.
If she didn't send the word...
...Allah for bid.
Thank goodness!
The bow.
Protect them!
- Bala!
Watch over yourselves!
Protect the kids.
Bala, are you alright?
I am alright.
Hatuns.
Barkın Bey.
Barkın?
Are you guys well?
We're well, thank goodness.
The scoundrel was hiding.
But we took care of him.
Thank you, Barkın Bey.
You arrived just in time.
Kill all of them besides Selvi, but...
...I'll kill anyone who even
touches the hair of Selvi.
Come on.
My bey, İnegöl...
...Osman Bey took it.
Damn it!
God damn it!
I got good news.
We got word from alps...
...Osman Bey,...
...Osman Bey has conquered İnegöl.
Praise be, my Osman Bey!
Thank goodness!
Thank for the good news, Barkın!
Bala, we should take care of your wound.
Let's get it done quickly
so that we can go to İnegöl.
Alahattin probably sent the word,
Osman Bey must be worried.
Alps, start a fire!
Come on!
He's got a lot of fractures.
We're going to have to open his skin.
Let's do whatever we
have to do, Kumral Abdal.
Tell me,...
...what should I go gather?
We did whatever we could for now.
We will pray.
His wounds will heal...
...and he'll be alright, if Allah permits.
If Allah permits.
My father.
We just got reunited, father.
You'll be well.
Don't go this early.
Don't go father.
Temur,...
...your father's a strong, tough man.
He'll recover,...
...if Allah permits.
You stay strong.
Be tough.
He is the great Gündüz Bey.
He is too tough for a couple of fractures.
He will be well, if Allah permits.
Right, Kumral Abdal?
If Allah permits.
Orhan and the hatuns are
in trouble right now.
They used the conquest as an
opportunity, those damn demons!
Don't you have any worry, my valiant.
Both your brother and mother
will come back without a scratch.
Look me in the eyes.
They will.
Thank Allah, I have no worries.
My father taught us how
to get out of any trouble.
Praise be, my valiant!
Praise be!
My brave valiant.
With enough effort, Allah gives aid.
We'll go after them.
Osman Bey is coming!
- Long live, Osman Bey!
- Allahu Akbar!
How are we going to exlpain
it to our Bey, Turgut Bey?
Gündüz Bey in one side,
Orhan is in the other.
He will know, Boran.
He will know the truth.
Son.
Come on.
Take him to the dungeon.
Yes, my bey!
I know the way.
Nikola
Alaattin.
Son, what are you doing here?
Tell me.
Bless your victories, Osman Bey!
We came to witness your victory, father.
Praise be!
Hatuns.
Bala, are you well?
It's no big deal, I'm well.
Everlasting victories, my bey!
Thank you all!
Kids.
Turgut Bey.
I saw everyone.
But I couldn't see my brother.
I couldn't see Aktemur.
Where are they?
Gündüz Bey is not well.
He's wounded badly, Osman Bey.
What are you saying?
Where is he?
HARMANKAYA CASTLE
Father,...
...son and the holy spirit.
God.
Son of God,...
...and the holy spirit.
How could...
...three deities be one?
How?
How could they be one?
There is no,...
...other deity.
There is no other God.
The only deity...
...is Allah.
...is Allah and nothing else.
Only Allah.
Allah...
...is the...
...greatest.
Sir, Commander Romanos is
here, and would like to see you.
Let him come in.
Let's not make the greatest commander
of Rome wait any longer.
Osman has played a big trick on us.
A very big one.
They have infitraded us.
İnegöl is in the dirty hands of Osman,
do you understand that, Kosses?
This is an insult to Rome!
Osman,...
...damn you!
What happens in Rome
stays in Rome, Romanos.
You know that better than anyone.
I know one other thing, Kosses.
If you hadn't gone soft
on Osman this much...
...if you weren't friendly towards him,...
...he was already destroyed.
Everything was an act.
We grew up together.
You know me best, Romanos.
A handful of lords could
not defeat one goatherd!
You smeared Rome with your greed.
You became friends with your enemies!
You know that I would never be friends
with a Turk witout an ulterior motive.
Then,...
...to show your ulterior motives
don't conflict with Rome's interests...
...you will solve this problem Kosses.
I will.
Don't worry.
Be we need to act carefully, brother.
If we underestimate Osman now,
we would show weakness.
Osman is a dangereous man.
We are...
...more dangereous, of course.
And we will show him that.
With your methods, or with
mine, it doesn't matter.
Sword,...
...or games.
Whatever it costs...
...we are going to take İnegöl from Osman.
Ambassador of the emperor
was on his way to stop the war.
He's about to be here, probably.
Hide your sword for now, Romanos.
We will defeat him with my methods.
Game against game.
What's on your mind, Kosses?
Let's welcome the ambassador
of the emperor first,...
...we'll talk about that later.
He's opening his eyes.
My father's opening his eyes.
Gündüz?
Gündüz.
Thank Allah!
I told you, he is the great Gündüz Bey.
He is going to conquer many castles.
He doen't die easily.
Ayşe.
My Gündüz.
Son.
My father.
Did we take İnegöl?
We did father.
Thanks to you.
Thank Allah!
Thanks to Allah!
Ayşe, see?
We took İnegöl.
Our son is with us alive and well.
Even if I die, I'll die happy.
Don't say that my bey.
We're yet to see the good
deeds ours son will accomplish.
Brother.
Are you well?
My bey,...
...he's got a lot of fractures.
I am well.
I am well, brother.
My brother just coquered İnegöl.
How could I not be well?
I'm well.
That's right, brother.
We have conquered İnegöl
It's ours now.
Thank goodness!
Kumral Abdal?
How is he?
He'll be well, if Allah permits, my bey.
You know the trust I have in you.
My brother is in your hands.
Brother, you rest for now.
I'll come back again.
May Allah bless you!
Get well soon, Gündüz Bey!
May Allah give you healing, Gündüz Bey!
You'll be alright soon, if Allah permits.
- Boran.
- My Bey?
We'll do the treatment of the alps here.
We'll stay in this castle
until my brother can walk
I am at your command, my bey!
Let's go.
Allahu Akbar Allahu Akabar
I am a witness that there
are no other Gods than Allah!
And I am a witness that Muhammad
is the messenger of Allah!
Rome is the greatest.
Rome is the greatest!
Ceasar is the greatest!
And I am a witness that Muhammad
is the messenger of Allah!
Rome is the greatest,
Ceasar is the greatest!
Aya Nikola is the greatest!
Hayyal Es Salah!
Hayyalel Felah!
The Great Allah,...
...you are the one who sent the book...
...you are the one who
makes the clouds move...
...you are the wisest.
My dear Allah,...
...you are the one who helped
us with defeating our enemies.
May you protect us against
the enemies at all times!
- Amen!
May you grant us with victory
against our enemies, Great Allah!
- Amen!
May you never allow them to
suppress our azans, dear Allah.
- Amen!
May you never allow them to
lift down our flags, dear Allah!
- Amen!
Amen, dear Allah!
Accept our prayers.
The İnegöl folk,...
...İnegöl...
...is the land of the Turks, from now on.
But,...
...don't ever be pessimistic.
We did not come here to be your enemies.
We did not come here to oppress.
In hour home, there is only prosperity,...
...and peace.
That's why...
...all of you can get back to your trade.
And never abandon farming.
Your rights,...
...lives,...
...and freedom...
...is in our hands.
What do you want?
We were going to come
to this castle like this, Kosses?
Time is running out, Romanos.
Tell your bey we're here.
Tell him we've got someone
important with us.
Tell your bey of yours...
...that the ambassador
of emperor Andronikos...
...himself...
...is here.
Ambassador Alkiz is here.
Devastation will occur
in battle, of course.
The demolished homes,...
...stores,...
...lands,...
...we wouldn't want to
have that effect you.
Therefore, let us know your outages.
We'll compensate for them with interest.
Know that we have seized
the properties of the soldiers,...
...commanders, and the traders...
...who drew their weapons
and shed the blood of my alps.
They will be given to the
veterans as tropies.
And we will help the martyr families.
As I've heard...
...some have fled from İnegöl once
they heard Turks were coming.
Send word to them now,...
...they can get back to their properties.
They can go back to do trade.
And they can worship freely.
In the castle or in the tribe.
We are always with the oppressed.
You are in our hands, from now on.
That is why...
...everyone can get back to work, now.
Go ahead.
Osman Bey,...
...I know you from your father.
My ancestors know your ancestor well, too.
We had always heard of
your fairness and mercy.
And I was sure you would follow the steps
of your ancestors. You didn't mislead me.
I am thankful to you on
the behalf of my people.
I would like you to know of my gratitute.
May Allah bless you, priest!
It is in the tradition of our prophet...
...to live by the book
and treat people...
...with fairness and mercy.
We try our best to follow that path.
Our ancestors were always
respectful of others' religon and lives.
Always be assured...
...that in these lands you will live with
us peacefully for the res of your lives.
Thank you, Osman Bey! Thank you!
May Allah bless you!
My Bey, they have sent an ambassador from
the emperorship and would like to see you.
Let them come in.
That is enough.
Welcome.
Osman Bey,...
...I am the shadow of the emperor
Andronikos, the ambassador Alkiz.
I greet you with respect.
May Allah bless you!
Tell me then,...
...what news have you
brought from your emperor?
To be honest...
...I was on the road to
meet you in your tribe.
But then bad news came and
I learned that you were in İnegöl.
And not as a guest...
...as the owner.
You took İnegöl.
That is true.
The İnegöl that was yours yesterday...
...belongst to Islam today.
Apparently, you're not afraid
of the wrath of our emperor.
It is admirable.
There is no problem that
can't be solved through peace.
Through peace?
With Romanos who kidnapped the unarmed
hatuns who were heading to tableland?
Or with...
...the lords who raided our
wedding and tried to kill us?
Tell me.
The lords did not do all of those things
all by themselves of course, but...
...tell me...
...who are we going to make peace with?
Or with the ambassador of
the emperor who set it all up?
Kosses,...
...I know very well that you
prepared an army against me.
That's why, there will be no peace.
Now, rest very well.
We'll discuss in detail in the evening...
...and tell you about our conditions.
Allahu Akbar.
May peace and the mercy
of Allah be upon you!
Al Fatiha.
Thank Allah!
Thank our Allah for granting us with this
conquest and with standing before him...
...peacefully in the courtyard.
Thank Allah!
He made the earth a masjid for us.
It should be the priorty of all Muslims to
pray to him and state his name everywhere.
The messenger of Allah says that
deeds depend on intentions.
A person who speaks his deeds
is for no good.
There are people who do good deeds
only to show off.
They are worse than those
who do no good deeds.
How, my sheik?
How can they be worse than ones
with no good deeds?
Lying is a greatest sin, Cerkutay.
The one who lies with his heart
has a bad fate.
This is secret shirk.
Our prophet says that they'll be judged
the first when the time comes.
May Allah forbid it, my sheik.
May Allah protect us from
being like that.
But who are they?
How will we stay back from becoming
that?
For example...
the people we know to be fallen
martyrs on the battlefield.
Martyrs. They say that they died for
Allah. They lie.
They only go to the battlefield
for glory.
They give their lives for their desires...
not for their Allah.
They'll be dragged to the ground...
and be sent to hell.
In Allah's place, martyrdom...
is being free of your desires
and fighting for Allah.
The other are those who learn science
and religion. Who teaches it.
They don't do it for Allah.
But only to be known as scholars.
They only read Qur-an to be acknowledged
by others.
They will also be dragged to hell.
The third is...
the ones who were destined with
great wealth.
When they are asked what they
did Allah...
they say that they shared their
money with the ones in need.
But Allah knows hearts and
sees the truth.
They shared their wealth to be known
as generous, not for Allah.
Those people will also get dragged
to hell.
May Allah forbid.
Hypocrisy is so disgusting that...
even the people with most deeds
face this fate.
Faith starts here.
Deeds are completed here.
Intentions are hidden in here.
No one can hide their intentions
from Allah.
Because the owner of the hearts
is Allah.
Every place we step on...
every battle we spill our battle on...
is to gain Allah's approval...
and spread Allah's words.
Allah owns everything.
We go to battle for Allah and we
win if Allah approves it.
İnegöl Castle
How is the situation?
Is there anyone critical?
We tended the wounds.
No one is heavily injured.
Give sherbet to them.
They need strength.
Are they healing the men they
wounded?
They are idiots.
Turks say that you can't rule
with tyranny, Romanos.
It's almost impossible to understand them.
I see that you still love them.
Let's not call it love.
Getting to know them from closer.
Getting to know your enemies
from closer.
Lord Kosses.
Boran.
Osman Bey expects you and the
ambassador in the church.
Let's go.
Mashallah to my valiants.
They are no different than
their ancestors.
Thank you, my children.
Thank you.
Holofira, thank you too.
You saved my alps.
It was easier to take
the castle, thanks to you.
I'm the one grateful, Osman Bey.
You saved my life for the second,
even third time!
Thank you.
Until my brother recovers,
we'll be here.
For that reasons, prepare.
Malhun, check my brother
all the time.
Don't worry, my bey. Gündüz Bey
and the castle are safe with us.
Thank you.
Bala, as the leader of the
sisters, you deserve congratulations.
Aygül and the sisters made
it easier for us.
They fought with the alps.
You revived the sisters,
thank you.
Thank you, my bey. But I'm not involved.
The power of faith revived them.
Thank you.
I'm going to the ambassador now.
I'll talk to him.
Be with my brother.
Inform me about everything.
Don't worry, father.
My uncle is with us.
My valiants.
We'll help the alps now. Then, we'll
go to my uncle.
Mashallah to my valiants.
I should leave.
Behold! Osman Bey!
Speak quickly.
At the wedding, you were invited to,
you killed the lords and took Bilecik.
Our emperor Andrenikos demands
a great compensation from you!
But I see that everything is out of
control. Aya Nikola is a captive.
-İnegöl is invaded!
-Not invaded.
Your kind does invasions.
You'll call it a conquest.
You'll call it a conquest, ambassador.
Whatever.
As the spokesman of Constantinople...
we demand eight carts
of gold...
return of İnegöl and Bilecik...
and lastly, release of Aya Nikola
and his soldiers.
Thank you.
You spoke quickly, ambassador.
I heard you.
But you'll hear me too.
We conquered Bilecik and İnegöl.
We didn't pillage.
We didn't kill the innocent.
For that reason, it's our
right of the sword.
Not just you, even your emperor
can't take it from me.
You are blowing the coals, Osman Bey!
I'm sure that there can be
a middle ground.
The ground is for the righteous.
Not with traitors.
Now, ambassador.
I have the castles.
And the villages around them.
If you want your soldiers.
I'll release them all
in return of gold.
But.
But except Nikola.
There is no gold to buy Nikola,
even in Constantinople.
Now.
İznik, Bursa, Constantinople;
if they want to trade with us...
they'll bring eight carts of gold to
my tribe, yearly.
Otherwise, the eastern market is
over for the western market.
It's so wrong.
What you are saying is
unacceptable, Osman Bey!
I'm not saying it for you to
accept it.
It's my offer.
Osman!
Taking a few castles and killing
a few lords blinded your eyes.
Don't forget this.
You are still a little Turkmen bey.
And I'll come at you with
a great army.
Then, you'll search for a hole
to hide in.
Romanos.
I'll be waiting for you in the field,
not in the castle.
Bring any army you want.
Me and my valiants are always
ready to face you.
Now think well.
You'll decide later.
And, do you know why
I invited you here?
This is the last day of
this church.
It's our conquest customs.
The biggest sanctuary of the castle
turns into a mosque.
For that reason...
make your last prayer.
Osman. Osman.
You should've seen it, brother.
It was a great battle.
Kumral Abdal told us about Bedr.
I felt like I was in it.
What are you doing, Orhan?
You made it bleed more.
Why are you talking about it as if
you don't know how much I wanted it?
I already missed it.
Stop crushing my heart with it.
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
No, Holafira.
I wasn't destined to.
Why would it be your fault?
But still, Alahaddin talked
about it and it hurt me.
I wanted to be in it.
You will, brother.
Many battles and conquests
are awating us.
Bursa and Constantinople are
awaiting us.
You'll be in them.
We will, brother. We'll fight
shoulder to shoulder.
No. This won't be. I should inform
Kumral Abdal.
Aygül.
There is nothing Kumral
can do.
It's time.
Call Osman.
Don't, father.
Not now.
We just reunited.
We just reunited, father.
-Son.
-Father.
My son.
No. Don't cry.
Don't cry.
Your father's prayers are accepted.
Your father has fallen a martyr
from a battle.
No. Don't cry.
-Ayşe. Ayşe.
-Gündüz!
Ayşe. Don't cry.
I'm leaving but...
I'm leaving you a son,
like a wolf.
I won't be worried.
My Gündüz!
What can I do without you?
Ayşe!
The light of my eyes.
You were always a good wife.
You have my blessing.
May Allah bless you too.
May Allah unite us
in the afterlife.
Inshallah.
Father!
My sisters.
We fought a lot, didn't we?
Give me your blessings.
It's yours, brother Gündüz.
You too.
It's yours, Gündüz Bey.
Turgut Bey, use some of the gold
to repair the damaged parts of the castle.
The rest will be shared between the
people who were harmed during the battle.
But İnegöl needs to revive.
For that reason, trade must
start at once.
It'll be protected
with our lives.
The people will be happy.
Inshallah.
And turning this church into a mosque
is your responsibility.
We don't forget the non-Muslims either.
Let's build a church fitting
their beliefs.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
Aygül.
He isn't well.
Osman should waste his time
with his little victory.
The war is just beginning.
I'll set such a game that
even the devil be jealous.
I'm awaiting your orders, Barkın Bey.
Osman thinks of beating
the lords.
You will go to the lord of Bursa...
and give this letter.
-Hüsamettin.
-My bey.
Praise Osman's victory to the
lord of Bursa.
Tell him that Osman claimed to be
the bey of the all Turkmens.
When he reads this letter, the lord
will be an enemy to Osman.
I'll praise him so much that he'll
want to kill Osman tomorrow.
Osman thinks he is powerful for
beating the little lords.
The lord of Bursa will do what
they couldn't.
Then, he'll learn about the world.
Söğüt, İnegöl. There will be blood.
Come on. Go quickly.
Brother.
Osman. Are you here?
I'm here, brother.
I'm here.
Are you good?
Brother.
Listen to me well.
What I left behind...
protect them.
It's time, Osman.
My mother, father, Savcı;
they are waiting for me.
What are you saying, brother?
What are you saying?
We'll go to many more conquests!
We'll fight a lot more!
We'll go to many more raids, brother!
No!
You...
you are...
you are my last foundation.
No. Don't say that.
Don't say that.
Look. You have your
children.
Your valiants.
I completed my duty, brother.
I'm in peace.
Don't worry.
No one should.
It's time for Gündüz Bey.
Osman.
My beautiful mother is waiting for me.
Give me your blessing.
Give me...
Brother.
You have my blessing.
Of course, you do.
You too, brother.
It's yours, brother.
It's yours, my wolf brother.
Be at ease.
What you left behind...
will be taken care of.
Father?
My father!
My father, I'm coming!
Your Gündüz is coming.
There is no God but Allah...
and...
is his prophet.
Brother?
Gündüz?
Father!
Gündüz!
Brother!
Wipe your tears.
You are a martyr's son.
Stand tall.
Be proud.
If you allow it...
I'll bury my brother
in İnegöl...
where he became a martyr.
Brother.
İnegöl Castle
If want to ask something.
Do you lose your when you get
separated?
Osman is a smart man.
He put you together
to not get lost.
You together wouldn't
make one man.
Idiots.
What are you talking about, coward?
Look, you are in our hands.
You can enter an unarmed captive's
dungeon only as two.
But I'm the coward, is that so?
I get it. You are begging to
get killed.
But you won't die
so easily, Nikola.
Osman Bey will kill you.
Don't be impatient.
Behold!
Osman Bey!
What's your decision?
It's impossible to accept your terms.
Alright.
Aya Nikola.
The back of the Kayı is filed
with your dagger wounds.
Your tyranny has reached the sky.
And the sky sent me to you...
as its fury.
You were always with the enemies
within...
you worked with the enemies outside.
You were with anyone who
were an enemy...
to the Turks.
But it's time for the sword
of Justice.
No, Osman Bey.
You can't do this!
-We came here for peace. You can't--
-Don't!
Don't! I don't beg for my life.
It's not your place to beg for me.
You won.
I lost.
And this is what a war is.
One wins...
the other loses.
But I'm very happy for hurting you,
Osman Bey.
Now, I'll die here.
Then, Rome will send a great
army after you.
Let's see, when the angry...
lions step on these lands...
what will your little wolves do?
I hear it.
I hear the footsteps.
And I'm ready.
They should come.
These lands are a home to
friends...
and a grave to the enemies.
The lions on a leash have no power
against hardened wolves.
The breath taken by tyrants like you
is torture to the oppressed.
The end of the tyrants is dying
under the sword of Justice.
It's time.
Allahu Akbar.
Osman Bey.
If your show is over, I'll return to
Constantinople...
to inform them about the
war you declared.
No.
Wait.
Wait there.
Don't go empty-handed.
Let it be a gift from me to your emperor.
Osman!
Your war with the lords is over.
Now...
you are in a war with an empire
that rules the whole world.
Inegöl is ours now!
But...
Şuşa in the east is also ours!
Gencebey!
Get enough alps with you.
And build your beylig there.
For the order of the world,
work for the state we'll found.
As you order, my bey.
These lands belong to the Turks,
or no one at all!
Thank you.
For Allah's words...
we became famous by the
revenge we'll take from the shirk!
Tend your wounds!
Sharpen your swords!
Now is not the time to stop
the conquests!
Now is time for jihad!
Allahu Akbar!
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com